Guide to the Hugh White papers, 1750-1933.
White, Hugh papers, 1750-1933.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hugh White papers, 1750-1933.
610
Hugh White, 1798-1870.
8.3 cubic ft.; 39 v.
Correspondence, letters, diaries, account books, tax receipts, deeds, inventories, contracts, surveys, land records, maps, photographs, church records, genealogical data, political papers, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, letters, diaries, account books, tax receipts, deeds, inventories, contracts, surveys, land records, maps, photographs, church records, genealogical data and other papers pertaining chiefly to White's involvement in land in northern New York, particularly the counties of Herkimer, Jefferson, Lewis, Oneida, Oswego, and St. Lawrence; material concerning the cement business at Chittenango and Greenkills, New York. Also, political papers (1840-1867), which include material on the Whig Party, patronage, and national and local issues.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Railroad builder, cement manufacturer, graduate of Hamilton College, and United States Congressional representative.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, letters, diaries, account books, tax receipts, deeds, inventories, contracts, surveys, land records, maps, photographs, church records, genealogical data and other papers pertaining chiefly to White's involvement in land in northern New York, particularly the counties of Herkimer, Jefferson, Lewis, Oneida, Oswego, and St. Lawrence; material concerning the cement business at Chittenango and Greenkills, New York. Also, political papers (1840-1867), which include material on the Whig Party, patronage, and national and local issues.
Also, material pertaining to the related Axtell, Duston, Lawrence, Mansfield, Mills, Niles, Porter, Van Wagenen, and Young families. Another subject is the 19th century spread of a family across the continent, with material reflecting American life and history of the period. White family papers include material on White's grandfather and grandson, also both named Hugh White. Major correspondents include William Constable, Hezekiah Beers Pierrepont, and William Constable Pierrepont (pertaining to New York State land patents) and James Buchanan, Washington Hunt, T. Batter King, William L. Marcy, William E. Seward, and Benjamin Wright.
Detailed item lists available in accession folder.
SUBJECTS
Names:
White, Hugh, 1798-1870.; Axtell family.; Buchanan, James, 1791-1868.; Constable, William, 1721-1791.; Duston family.; Hunt, Washington.; King, T. Batter.; Lawrence family.; Mansfield family.; Marcy, William L.; Mills family.; Niles family.; Pierrepont, Hezekiah Beers.; Pierrepont, William Constable.; Porter family.; Seward, William E.; Van Wagenen family.; White family.; Wright, Benjamin.; Young family.; Hamilton College.; United States.Congress.House.; Whig Party (U.S.)
Subjects:
Real property--New York (State)--Herkimer County.; Real property--New York (State)--Jefferson County.; Real property--New York (State)--Lewis County.; Real property--New York (State)--Oneida County.; Real property--New York (State)--Oswego County.; Real property--New York (State)--St.Lawrence County.; Cement industries--New York (State)--Chittenango.; Cement industries--New York (State)--Greenkills.; Politics, Practical--New York (State); Patronage, Political--New York (State); Family--New York (State); Railroads--United States.; Migration, Internal--United States.; Industries--New York (State)--Chittenango.; Industries--New York (State)--Greenkills.; Land grants.
Places:
New York (State)--Religious life and customs.; New York (State)--Politics and government.; United States--Description and travel--19th century.; United States--History--19th century.; New York (State)--Genealogy.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Account books.; Deeds.; Inventories.; Surveys.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collections #604, #610, #654, #898, and #1315.
Because this collection has combined multiple accessions, received at multiple times, box numbers in the printed guide may not match up.
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a partial finding aid.
  Not all the material in the collection is covered by this guide.
- Volume (Volume 604 - 1)
- Pamphlets (Box 610 - 1-2)
- 1778-1829 (Box 610 - 3)
- 1830-1840 (Box 610 - 4)
- 1841-1846 (Box 610 - 5)
- 1847-1855 (Box 610 - 6)
- 1855-1864 (Box 610 - 7)
- 1865-1878 (Box 610 - 8)
- 1879-1899 (Box 610 - 9)
- 1899-1927 (Box 610 - 10)
- 1865-1921, Cement, Greenkills, Cancelled Checks (Box 610 - 11)
- Unidentified (Box 610 - 12)
- Undated folders, 1-24 (Box 610 - 13)
- Undated folders, 25-37 (Box 610 - 14)
- Journals, Diaries, ck. books (Box 610 - 15)
- Maps, Broadsides (Box 610 - 16)
- Undescribed Material (Box 654 - 1-2)
- Volumes 1-5 (Box 654 - 3)
- Volumes 6-8, 13-17 (Box 654 - 4)
- Volumes 18-22, 24-27 (Box 654 - 5)
- Volumes 28-34, 36-38 (Box 654 - 6)
- Loose Volumes (Volume 9-12, 23, 35)
- White, Pierrepont genealogies and letters (Box In 25, Folder 654m)
- Undescribed Material (Box 898 - 1-2)
- Undescribed Material (Box 1315 - 1)